export const ECONOMICSA2014 = [

{
id: "question1",
question:  "1. Human want are unlimited because",
A: "production is inadequate",
B: "resources have alternative uses",
C: "new wants always rise",
D: "resources are limited",
answer: "D. resources are limited",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question2",
question:  "2. A basic economic problem of any society is",
A: "high level of illiteracy",
B: "irregular power supply",
C: "population growth",
D: "resource allocation",
answer: "D. resource allocation",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question3",
question:  "3. In a centrally planned economy, what to produce is",
A: "determined by the forces of demand and spply",
B: "driven by profit motive",
C: "determined by consumers",
D: "the responsibility of state's bureaucrats",
answer: "D. the responsibility of state's bureaucrats",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question4",
question:  "4. Which of the following is related to resources allocation in an economy?",
A: "how to produce",
B: "what to produce",
C: "for whom to produce",
D: "efficient use of inputs",
answer: "D. efficient use of inputs",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question5",
question:  "5. Which of following is not a feature of socialism?",
A: "Collective ownership of productive resources",
B: "Freedom of enterprise",
C: "production is not based on the profit motive",
D: "Maximization of public welfare",
answer: "B. Freedom of enterprise",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question6",
question:  "6. Households make economic decisions because they want to",
A: "make more profit",
B: "increase their salaries and wages",
C: "increase their purchases",
D: "maximize their satisfaction",
answer: "D. maximize their satisfaction",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question7",
question:  "7. State-owned enterprises are more common in:",
A: "centrally planned economies",
B: "mixed economies",
C: "capitalist economies",
D: "developed economies",
answer: "A. centrally planned economies",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question8",
question:  "8. A normal supply curve has a positive slope which indicates that",
A: "sellers are willing to sell more at a lower price",
B: "sellers are indifferent to prices",
C: "sellers are willing to sell more at a higher price",
D: "there is always a fixed supply",
answer: "C. sellers are willing to sell more at a higher price",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question9",
question:  "9. To control inflation, the central bank of a country may adopt",
A: "an expansionary monetary policy",
B: "a restrictive monetary policy",
C: "an increased wage policy",
D: "a deficit financing policy",
answer: "B. a restrictive monetary policy",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question10",
question:  "10. Disposable income is the income earned",
A: "by the nationals of a country resident within the country",
B: "from productive activities of nationals of a country both at home and abroad",
C: "when personal income tax is deducted from personal income",
D: "when the gross income of an individual is added to person income tax",
answer: "C. when personal income tax is deducted from personal income",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question11",
question:  "11. Livestock production in West Africa is hindered mainly by",
A: "inadequate demand",
B: "use of traditional implements",
C: "land tenure system",
D: "pests and diseases",
answer: "D.pests and diseases",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question12",
question:  "12. The components of a three-sector economy are",
A: "banks, schools and hospitals",
B: "workers, producers and marketers",
C: "households, firms and the government",
D: "producers, retailers and wholesalers",
answer: "C. households, firms and the government",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question13",
question:  "13. A declining population is one in which the population is",
A: "experiencing a high rate of emigration",
B: "made up of large number of old people",
C: "not producing enough goods",
D: "not contributing enough to the national income",
answer: "B. made up of large number of old people",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question14",
question:  "14. Which of the following agencies help to stabilize farmers’ income?",
A: "Local government authorities",
B: "Trade unions",
C: "Marketing boards",
D: "Co-operative organizations",
answer: "C. Marketing boards",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question15",
question:  "15. Other things being equal, an increase in supply will lead to",
A: "a fall in price and an increase in quantity bought and sold",
B: "an increase in price and increase in quantity bought and sold",
C: "a fall in price and a fall in quantity bought and sold",
D: "an increase in quantity supplied and demanded only",
answer: "D.an increase in quantity supplied and demanded only",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question16",
question:  "16. Examples of joint stock banks are",
A: "commercial banks",
B: "co-operative credit societies",
C: "central banks",
D: "development banks",
answer: "A. commercial banks",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question17",
question:  "17. Which of the following is not a characteristic of a developing country?  High",
A: "real per capital income",
B: "level of primary production",
C: "population growth rate",
D: "level of illiteracy",
answer: "A. real per capital income",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question18",
question:  "18. Goods consumed out of habit have",
A: "elastic demand",
B: "perfectly elastic demand",
C: "inelastic demand",
D: "unitary elastic demand",
answer: "C. inelastic demand",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question19",
question:  "19. Which of the following items is not a recurrent expenditure?",
A: "building of schools and colleges",
B: "maintenance of school buildings",
C: "payment of teachers’ salaries",
D: "purchase of stationery for examination",
answer: "A. building of schools and colleges",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question20",
question:  "20. If the coefficient of price elasticity of demand is 0.1, demand is",
A: "elastic",
B: "inelastic",
C: "zero elastic",
D: "unitary elastic",
answer: "B. inelastic",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question21",
question:  "21. The profit of a producer is the difference between",
A: "total cost and marginal cost",
B: "total revenue and total cost",
C: "average cost and total cost",
D: "price and total cost",
answer: "B. total revenue and total cost",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question22",
question:  "22. The rate of increase in utility is",
A: "average utility",
B: "increasing utility",
C: "total utility",
D: "marginal utility",
answer: "D.marginal utility",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question23",
question:  "23. The supply of tea is linearly presented as P = 0.2Q, where P is the price and Q is the quantity. What is P when Q = 25?",
A: "$0.08",
B: "$5.00",
C: "$25.02",
D: "$125",
answer: "B. $5.00",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question24",
question:  "24. Increase in supply due to changes in plant size will take place only in the",
A: "normal time",
B: "long run",
C: "market period",
D: "short run",
answer: "B. long run",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question25",
question:  "25. The long – run average cost curve is made up of several short-run",
A: "marginal and average cost curves",
B: "average cost curves",
C: "average variable cost curves",
D: "average variable and total cost curves",
answer: "D.average variable and total cost curves",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question26",
question:  "26. From the table, the mean of the distribution is",
A: "2.2",
B: "2.5",
C: "3.2",
D: "4.5",
answer: "C. 3.2",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question27",
question:  "27. What is the median of the distribution?",
A: "5",
B: "4",
C: "3",
D: "2",
answer: "C. 3",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question28",
question:  "28. Co-operative societies formed to market the output of their members are called",
A: "Consumers' co-operative societies",
B: "Wholesale co-operative societies",
C: "Credit and thrift co-operative societies",
D: "Producers' co-operative societies",
answer: "D.Producers' co-operative societies",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question29",
question:  "29. Money will serve as a standard of deferred payment if it is",
A: "homogeneous",
B: "durable",
C: "easily recognized",
D: "stable in value",
answer: "D.stable in value",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question30",
question:  "30. Due to an increase in price, a seller increases the quantity offered for sale from 400 units. What is the percentage change in quantity supplied?",
A: "1 %",
B: "7.5%",
C: "12.5%",
D: "20%",
answer: "C. 12.5%",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question31",
question:  "31. Which of the following will increase the nominal value of national income?",
A: "High rate of inflation",
B: "increase in the value of money",
C: "Increase in import",
D: "High rate of subsistence production",
answer: "B. increase in the value of money",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question32",
question:  "32. Cyclical unemployment is one associated with",
A: "inadequate information",
B: "trade fluctuations",
C: "structural changes",
D: "seasonal changes",
answer: "B. trade fluctuations",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question33",
question:  "33. Which of the following best defines inflation?",
A: "Cyclical increase in prices",
B: "Periodic increase in prices",
C: "Persistent increase in prices",
D: "Occasional increase in prices",
answer: "C. Persistent increase in prices",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question34",
question:  "34. Perfect knowledge of events in a perfect market will be made possible by the existence of",
A: "many buyers and sellers",
B: "homogeneous products",
C: "means of communication",
D: "large number of traders",
answer: "C. means of communication",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question35",
question:  "35. An increase in the price of a commodity from $10 to $15 leads to an increase in the quantity supplied from 10 units to 15 units. The price elasticity of supply is",
A: "0",
B: "0.5",
C: "1",
D: "5",
answer: "C. 1",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question36",
question:  "36. Economic development may be hindered if there is",
A: "a high pool of skilled labour",
B: "a high rate of economic growth",
C: "political stability",
D: "rapid population growth",
answer: "D.rapid population growth",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},

{
id: "question37",
question:  "37. Which of the following types of unemployment results from changes in the pattern of aggregate demand?",
A: "Technological unemployment",
B: "Structural unemployment",
C: "Frictional unemployment",
D: "Seasonal unemployment",
answer: "B. Structural unemployment",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question38",
question:  "38. Which of the following is not a reason countries import goods?",
A: "Differences in natural endowments",
B: "the law of absolute advantage",
C: "Differences in tastes",
D: "The love for other nations",
answer: "A. Differences in natural endowments",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question39",
question:  "39. Provision of short-term loans to solve balance of payments problems is done by the",
A: "International Finance Corporation",
B: "International Monetary Fund",
C: "International Bank for Reconstruction and Development",
D: "African Development Bank",
answer: "B. International Monetary Fund",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question40",
question:  "40. West African countries are experiencing worsening terms of trade because",
A: "they are primary producers",
B: "their currencies are overvalued",
C: "they import less machines",
D: "they are tertiary producers",
answer: "A. they are primary producers",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question41",
question:  "41. Which of the following statements is correct?",
A: "As total utility increases, the marginal utility also increases",
B: "The marginal utility is a always zero whenever the total utility reaches the maximum",
C: "The total utility is at maximum whenever marginal utility is at it's maximum",
D: "There is no relationship between total utility and the marginal utility",
answer: "B. The marginal utility is a always zero whenever the total utility reaches the maximum",
correctLetter: "B",
correctOption: 2,
},

{
id: "question42",
question:  "42. A change in the quantity demanded of a given commodity is determined by the",
A: "size of the population",
B: "income of the consumer",
C: "price of the commodity",
D: "taste and fashion",
answer: "C. price of the commodity",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question43",
question:  "43. The likely implication of the devaluation of a country’s currency is that",
A: "exports of such a country become cheaper",
B: "importation of goods into such a country becomes cheaper",
C: "the value of such a country's currency rises",
D: "foreign goods are attracted into the country",
answer: "A. exports of such a country become cheaper",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question44",
question:  "44. International trade is desirable because it",
A: "may lead to overproduction",
B: "brings about over-dependence of countries on one another",
C: "provides foreign market for local goods",
D: "brings about unhealthy competition and rivalries",
answer: "C. provides foreign market for local goods",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question45",
question:  "45. A financial institution established for the purpose of providing specialzed services like acceptance of bills of exchange and equipment leasing is known as",
A: "Merchant Bank",
B: "Development Bank",
C: "Central Bank",
D: "Insurance Company",
answer: "A. Merchant Bank",
correctLetter: "A",
correctOption: 1,
},

{
id: "question46",
question:  "46. Which of the following functions of money is mostly affected during inflation?",
A: "Medium of exchange",
B: "Unit of Account",
C: "Store of value",
D: "Standard of deferred payment",
answer: "C. Store of value",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question47",
question:  "47. Precautionary motive for holding money is to",
A: "meet daily and regular transactions",
B: "take advantage of changes in the prices of goods and services",
C: "cover unforeseen events",
D: "cover expenses on house rent",
answer: "C. cover unforeseen events",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question48",
question:  "48. Which of the following measures will not encourage industrialization in West Africa?",
A: "Taking over of all forms of industries by the government",
B: "provision of social infrastructure",
C: "Giving tax incentives, especially to infant industries",
D: "Using tariffs to discourage the use of imported items",
answer: "C. Giving tax incentives, especially to infant industries",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question49",
question:  "49. The concentration of many firms of a particular industry in a particular area is known as",
A: "location of industry",
B: "amalgamation of industries",
C: "localization of industries",
D: "nationalization of industry",
answer: "C. localization of industries",
correctLetter: "C",
correctOption: 3,
},

{
id: "question50",
question:  "50. Which of the following is not an effect of the discovery of mineral resources in an area?",
A: "increase in wealth",
B: "overcrowding",
C: "increase in crime rate",
D: "under population",
answer: "D.under population",
correctLetter: "D",
correctOption: 4,
},


]